# 新疆·乌鲁木齐
(Urumqi, Xinjiang)
# 哇
Wow
# 好香啊
It smells so good
# 在这儿都能闻到洋葱的味道
I can smell the onion even from here
# 大哥 这是多少斤羊肉
Hey bro, how much mutton is there?
# 这是
There are...
# 30斤
30 jin (= 15kg)
# 30斤羊肉放在这一锅里炒
Cooking 30 jin of mutton in this pot?
# 是呀
Yeah
# 厉害
Amazing
# 你们是哪里人
Where are you from
# 山东人
Shandong
# 山东的？
Shandong?
# 对
Yes
# 山东的一般都吃海鲜？
Do people in Shandong eat a lot of seafood?
# 靠近海边的喜欢吃海鲜
Those living close to the sea like seafood
# 朝里面一点也不是很喜欢吃海鲜
Those living inside don't quite like seafood
# 我认识好几个山东的
I know some people from Shandong
# 都喜欢吃海鲜
They all love seafood
# 一般青岛的会比较多 青岛 烟台 威海
It's mostly people from Qingdao. Qingdao, Yantai and Weihai
# 会比较多
Lots of (seafood lovers)
# 是这样的
I see
# 对
Yeah
# 大哥用铁锹在这儿翻羊肉
This bro is cooking mutton with a shovel
# 这边用的羊肉 都是肥瘦相间的
The mutton here is all mixed of fat and lean parts
# 是的
Yeah, right
# 我告诉你 路过抓饭店
Let me tell you. If you go past a pilaf restaurant
# 不得不吃
you'll have to stop by and eat
# 因为它这个香味 不仅有羊肉的香味
Because of the fragrance. It's not just mutton
# 还有米香味 还有洋葱的香味
Also the fragrance of rice, and fragrance of onion
# 真是三者融合为一体
Such a perfect fusion of the three
# 吸引你赶快来吃呀
which attracts you to here to enjoy
# 现在我们就等着吃手抓饭了
Now we are waiting for the pilaf
# （一对专门来吃抓饭的老夫妻）
(And old couple coming for pilaf)
# 今天开饭晚了
Today we are opening late
(And old couple coming for pilaf)
# 没事
It's fine
# 周末 开饭还要晚半个小时
It's weekend. It opens half an hour later than usual.
# 没事 我们坐一会儿
It's fine. We can sit here for a while
# 在家也没事
There's nothing to do at home anyway
# 我们从开业第二年 就开始（过来）吃
We are eating here since 2nd year of their business
# 一直吃到现在
All the way till now
# 十多年老顾客
Long term customers for over a decade
# 都是开车来吃
We always drive here for the food
# 开车来吃
Drive here for the food
# 我们也不在这儿周边 在乌鲁木齐市住
We don't live around. We live in downtown Urumqi
# 开了多久来的
How long does it take to drive?
# 他开店第二年就来吃了
We came here in their second year
# 亲戚嘛
... some relatives
# 就一块拉来吃
They took us here to eat together
# 我们主要是每个星期都来
Mainly, we come here every week
# 他要是没有车 我们都坐公交
we always took a bus until he had a car
# 现在有车了 我们就开车来
Now we have cars, so we drive here
# 公交也近 坐到那个地方
The bus station is close too. Just take a bus to that place
# 再走过来得二百米
and then walk for 200m
# 二百米 是
200 meters, yeah
# 刚才这个阿姨说
The auntie told us that
# 这个肉新鲜到什么程度
the mutton here is so fresh that
# 就是刚宰来的嘛
it's freshly butchered
# 拿来的时候 肉还是热的
and the meat was still warm when delivered here
# 走吧
Let's go
# 就是在新疆吃抓饭 吃羊肉
You got to eat pilaf and mutton in Xinjiang
# 记得吃点皮芽子
Remember to have some "piyazi"
# 哦 洋葱
Oh, you mean onions
# 也叫皮芽子
Also called "piyazi"
# 要多少钱的手抓饭 说
How much (pilaf do you want)? Say it
# 要一盘 大盘加肉 再要四个烤串
I'd like a large plate with extra meat, and 4 skewers
# 65元
# 大盘加肉40元
# 烤串5元/根
65 yuan?
(Large plate with extra meat: 40yuan)
(skewers: 5 yuan each)
# 对 对 对
Right, right, right
# 过去了
Paid
# 我们今天的目标
Our objective today...
# 大盘 加肉 抓饭
Large plate. Extra meat. Pilaf
# 还没到
Still waiting...
# 来了 来了
It's coming
# 谢谢
Thank you
# 不够再加米
Add rice if that's not enough
# 可以再加米
I can add rice?
# 可以加
You can
# 谢谢
Thank you
# 这个闻到味就饿了吧
Getting hungry as soon as you smell it
# 米是先浸泡了
The rice is pre-soaked
# 然后和处理好的羊肉放在一起炖煮
And then cooked together with the processed mutton
# 你看 粒粒分明
Look, every grain is clear
# 因为米饭是和羊肉一起蒸出来的
As the rice is steamed together with mutton
# 所以说 这个米饭
So you know, the rice
# 一点都不会干
doesn't taste dry at all
# 有油的滑润感
It feels like greased with the oil
# 真的是特别香
Really flavorful!
# 里面放了两种萝卜
There are two types of carrots inside
# 一个是稍微橘色一点 一个是稍微黄色一点
One looks orange, and the other looks yellow
# 炖的特别烂 而且还有油水
It's stewed to really soft. And it's juicy inside
# 大口吃肉 大口吃饭
Eating huge meat! Eating huge rice!
# 羊肉特别软烂 而且不腥也不膻
The mutton is really soft and tender. And there's no gamey odor at all
# 吃起来就是这种原汁原味
It's full of the original flavor
# 可能在很久之前吃抓饭是用手抓着吃的
Perhaps pilaf was eaten with hands a long time ago
# 现在可以用小勺了 （还有筷子）
Now we can use spoons
(And chopsticks)
# （为什么吃的画面很少）
(Why are there so few eating scenes?)
# （只怪抓饭太香）
(Because the pilaf is too tasty)
# （工作日五六锅 周末四五锅）
(Weekdays: 5 to 6 pots sold)
(Weekend: 4 to 5 pots sold)
# 你以为我们今天是来吃抓饭的吗
You thought we came for pilaf today?
# 我们今天是来吃肉的
We came for meat today
# 关 注 雪 鱼 探 店
(Subscribe)